MISAKI TIFFANY SHIMIZU

• 416.524.6692 | tshimizumisaki@gmail.com | www.tiffanyshimizu.com | 🛡 Ontario, Canada •



linkedin.com/in/tiffany-shimizu/



github.com/misakishimizu

FRONT END DEVELOPER PROFILE

I am a front-end software developer that creates functional and responsive web designs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and API integrations. I have an educational background in Early Childhood Studies and have worked in the customer service / retail industry for 10+ years. My strong communication and problem-solving skills allow me to find new solutions and explore new ways to code. In my spare time, I love to watch movies and spend time with my dog Parker. I also enjoy eating food so you will find me testing new recipes in the kitchen! Seeking to become the next Front-end Developer at your company.

SKILLS SUMMARY

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JavaScript (ES6, ES5) | React | JQuery | RESTful API | Node.js | Version Control (Git) | Responsive Designs | Performance Testing | Load testing & Debugging | Communication | Problem Solving | Customer Service | Critical Thinking | Continuous Learner | Time Management | Decision Making | Teamwork & Collaboration

RECENT PROJECTS

Daily Dad Jokes (Group Programming)

Site Link

GitHub Link

This project uses React to build an interactive app where users can select a category of photos, input their own dad jokes, and display the results through a carousel. Through the use of Git, we were able to collaborate and successfully produce the request from the client.

Word Search (Solo)

Site Link

GitHub Link

This app uses the Merriam Webster API and is coded with React and Axios calls. The user is able to look up a word in the search bar and the API will pull the results and display a definition, pronunciation, and phonetics.

The Music Mood Generator (Pair Programming)

<u>Site Link</u>

GitHub Link

This interactive app utilizes JavaScript, API, and SASS to allow users to select a mood and generate a song based on their selected mood. Users are able to view data pulled from the API that displays the album cover, song title, artist, and an audio clip of the song.

WORK HISTORY

Juno College of Technology | Web Development Mentor (Volunteer)

2022 - Present

- Assisted over 10+ current students in the Web Development BootCamp during Alumni Office Hours
- Provided resources and advice on how to resolve an issue on their in-class projects with JavaScript & React

Community Foundation of Mississauga | Event Assistant (Mississauga, Ontario)

2020 - 2021

- Coordinated pre-and post-event planning with a team of 25 staff serving 150 customers
- Juggled multiple projects and tasks to ensure high quality and timely delivery
- Procured a team of 30 volunteers to help support two events
- Created two event websites according to established standards and with high accuracy and efficiency

Uniqlo | Sales Associate (Mississauga, Ontario)

2018 - 2020

- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and advertising collateral
- Delivered a high level of assistance by locating products and checking the store system for merchandise at other sites
- Maintained organized, presentable merchandise to drive continuous sales

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Juno College of Technology | Web Development Bootcamp | Toronto, Canada Humber College | Graduate Certificate Event Management | Toronto, Canada 2021 - 2022

2020 - 2021